Oussama ABOULHASSAN

Python & Full-Stack Web Developer

I am an intermediate senior Python developer and a full-stack web developer and I also hold a bachelor's degree in chemistry offering 3 years of in-depth experience in development and exceptional analytical and critical thinking skills.

EXPERIENCES

Contracteur, Marrakech, MA *Full-Stack Web Developer*

Oct 2021 - Présent

- Successfully designed and developed more than 20 scalable, secure and globalized web applications to ensure the continuity of all business processes and customer satisfaction.
- Assisted several students in the development of several websites and online applications and discussed each step I take for a deeper understanding.

Freelancer, Marrakech, MA Python Backend Developer

Septembre 2020 – Novembre 2022

- Developed web application back end components while communicating with 10+ clients to identify their needs/goals and work on meeting them.
- Created a web tester for testing the web app developed for clients before delivering the product.
- Consumed APIs while utilizing Python requests to read numerous JSON reports and made telegram bots return the API get request
- Obtained adequate experience in reviewing Python code for running the troubleshooting test-cases and bug issues, acquiring all necessary skills.
- Developed, tested, and debugged software tools utilized by 100+ clients and internal customers to facilitate and easier process and user experience.

Volunteer Assistant, MA (remote)

April 2020 – May 2020

- Helped organize orders by contacting consumers and processing the payment.
- Effectively managed the customer orders and listed them in an excel sheet.
- Communicated clearly with the supervisors on a video chat in both English and French.

PROJECTS

- Nutrition Web Application: Built a web app that figure out your ideal diet based on your calories input. (https://dietondemand.up.railway.app)
- ❖ Ai telegram bot: ChatGPT based Ai integrated with telegram bot.
- Automated upload: Created an automated way to upload design to Redbubble based on selenium.
- Rock paper scissors quiz: RPS with the machine and the loser have to answer a quiz question.

Marrakech, Morocco. +212 603-430790

oussamaaboulhassan26@gmail.

https://linkedin.com/in/oussam aab

https://github.com/oussamaaboulhassan

TECHNOLOGIES

Python, Go Lang, HTML3, CSS5, JavaScript, Selenium, Django, Flask, Node JS, Telegram Bots, JSON, Bootstrap 5.2, Tailwind, MySQL, Mongo DB, Krita, Adobe PS, Illustrator, MS Word, Excel & PPT, Git, Github Codespace, Heroku, Railway.

LANGUAGES

English: Fluent (British accent)

French: Fluent Arabic: Native

EDUCATION

BSc Chimie

BS in Chemistry at the faculty of science Semlalia.

Graduated in October 2022

Marrakech, MA

 Python 12 months online courses in Udemy.

Completed in March 2020
Marrakech, MA

SKILLS

Hard worker fast learner Leadership Communication Critical thinking Flexibility Problem-solving